schrodinger.com 2019-06-19

# Privacy Policies | Schrödinger

**Last Updated: June 5, 2018**

 **Privacy Policy**

Schrödinger recognizes privacy and security as being a concern for most individuals. This privacy policy describes how Schrödinger, LLC and its corporate affiliates (“Schrödinger” or “we”) collect, use, share and transfer your personal information.

Please read this privacy policy carefully before providing any personal information to us. Schrödinger reserves the right to modify this privacy policy at any time by posting the changes on this Web Site (defined below).

 **What information is collected?**

We receive and store any information you provide to us including information you enter on our Web Site. As used herein, “Web Site” means any web site operated or managed by Schrödinger including, without limitation, schrodinger.com, schrodinger.co.jp, PyMOL.org, and the Schrödinger pages of chj.tbe.taleo.net (collectively, this or our “Web Site”). This Web Site collects personal information that visitors voluntarily provide to this Web Site. Typically, visitors provide personal information to this Web Site to request a service of Schrödinger. For example, visitors to this Web Site are asked to provide personal information, such as name, title, institution, address, email address and other contact information, when they request a sales quote for Schrödinger software, ask for a new logon account, register for a symposium, webinar, or campaign, or send Schrödinger an email message via any of the links on this Web Site. Visitors with a logon account are required to provide their email and password before they are permitted to access certain features, such as downloading Schrödinger software or consulting our support documentation. From time to time, visitors may also be invited to respond to an optional survey or questionnaire on this Web Site.

This privacy policy also covers information collected from individuals who are interested in an employment position with Schrödinger (Applicants). Applicants may submit their information either through the online application forms accessible on our Careers page, or by sending us an email with information they deem relevant (e.g., resume, cover letter). Online application forms contain a number of required, mandatory fields, which Applicants must complete in order to create a profile and apply for a position, namely: email, password, first name, last name, source where the Applicant found out about the position, eligibility to work, highest education level, and resume upload. We ask that, as an Applicant, you avoid submitting information which may qualify as sensitive information under applicable law, except where the collection of such information is legally required or authorized (e.g., if you decide to become part of a voluntary equal opportunity initiative for your own benefit, such as by completing the Voluntary Equal Opportunity Questionnaire during your application), such as: information on race, ethnicity, sex life or sexual orientation, medical or health information (including disability status), genetic information or biometric information (for the purpose of unique identification), political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership, judicial data such as criminal convictions and offenses, or other information that may be construed as sensitive under applicable law.

Information about your computer and Internet browser is also automatically collected by our web server and by third-party servers that provide website analytics services to Schrödinger. This information includes your IP address, domain name, browser type and version, operating system, access times and referring Web site address. We use JavaScript and/or may place “Web beacons” (also known as “clear gifs”) on our Web pages to help us collect this information. Schrödinger generally uses this information to measure the usage of this Web Site (such as the number of visitors, average time spent on this Web Site, and pages viewed), and to improve this Web Site’s content.

 **What about cookies?**

Like most Web sites, our Web Site uses cookies to enable basic Web functions. Our Web Site’s cookies store information on the hard drive or in the memory of a visitor's computer. The cookies issued by our Web Site to a visitor’s browser allow us to compile usage statistics for this Web Site and keep track of user preferences for this Web Site. For visitors with a logon account, the information stored in the cookie also permits our Web Site to verify the visitor’s logon name and password, in order to enable access to the password-protected portions of this Web Site.

You have choices with respect to cookies. By modifying your browser preferences, you have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is sent, or to reject all cookies. Please note, however, that if you choose to reject all cookies, this Web Site will have no means to verify your logon account, and you will not be able to use the password-protected areas of this Web Site. When you provide personal information on this Web Site, you are submitting that information to Schrödinger.

 **How is my information used?**

We collect and process information about you for the following reasons

a. Because you voluntarily provide this information;   
b. Because this information is necessary to take steps at your request prior to entering into an employment or internship;   
c. Because this information is of particular importance to us and we have a specific legitimate interest under law to process it;   
d. To comply with a legal obligation; or   
e. Where necessary to protect the vital interests of any person.

Where the processing concerns information you voluntarily provided to us, or the processing is based on your consent, you may withdraw your consent at any time.

Schrödinger uses your personal information in order to manage your account, to process your registration, orders and bills, to respond to your questions and specific requests and to support Schrödinger software and its licensees and users. We use the information you provide to us to design new products and improve existing products, and to provide you with information, advice and purchase recommendations. We may also use your personal information to preserve our other legitimate interests, for example, for Schrödinger’s administrative purposes, aggregate management reporting, internal training, and as generally required to conduct our business within Schrödinger.

We may also use the information we collect to inform you of other products and services available from Schrödinger LLC. You may receive a communication from us by email or direct mail. If you do not want to receive such information, simply follow the directions contained in each such communication to remove your name from our mailing list. You may also contact us at [**remove@schrodinger.com**](mailto:remove@schrodinger.com).

Finally, Schrödinger may research our users' demographics and interests based on the information provided to us. We do this to better understand and serve our users. Schrödinger may share this data with our business partners.

When collecting information about Applicants, Schrödinger only processes information that is strictly necessary for the purpose of assessing the Applicant’s eligibility and fitness for the employment position that the Applicant applies for. We kindly ask that you not send us any information that is not directly relevant to this purpose.

Schrödinger may also use and share personal information as we believe to be necessary or appropriate: (a) under applicable law, including laws outside your country of residence; (b) to comply with legal process; (c) to respond to requests from public and government authorities including public and government authorities outside your country of residence; (d) to enforce Schrödinger’s terms and conditions; (e) to protect Schrödinger’s operations or those of any of our affiliates; (f) to protect Schrödinger’s rights, privacy, safety or property and /or that of our affiliates, you or others; and (g) to allow Schrödinger to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain.

Sharing your personal information may include transferring personal information to other countries (including countries other than where you are based that have a different data protection regime than is found in the country where you are based). If you are located in the European Economic Area (the “EEA”) this may include countries outside of the EEA.

 **With whom does Schrödinger share my information?**

Visitors who register online for Schrödinger’s symposia and webinars will have their personal contact information included on an attendee list that may be shared with the event’s sponsors (if any), and possibly with other meeting attendees. Event attendees may therefore be contacted after the event by the event’s sponsors and others.

Schrödinger may also share personal information in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be violating our Web Site’s Terms of Use or may be violating Schrödinger's or other's rights or causing injury to or interference with Schrödinger's or other's property. Schrödinger may also share or access personal information if required or permitted to do so by law or when we believe in good faith such action is necessary to comply with the law, respond to claims or comply with legal process served on Schrödinger. Personal information may be shared to a third party as part of a merger, acquisition, financing, or sale of company assets, as well as in the event of an insolvency, bankruptcy or receivership in which personal information could be assigned or otherwise transferred to one or more third parties as one of the business assets of Schrödinger. Schrödinger may also share aggregated user statistics in order to describe our Web Site to prospective business partners, advertisers, and other third parties, and for other lawful purposes.

 **How long is my information stored?**

Schrödinger will retain personal information for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this privacy policy unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law. Schrödinger may also retain your information for the purpose of considering whether your skills are suitable for other opportunities. If you do not wish us to do this, please contact us at [**remove@schrodinger.com**](mailto:remove@schrodinger.com). We may remove personal information for inactive accounts from our database, subject to any applicable legal or regulatory obligations. Furthermore, Schrödinger may delete personal information about you (including your CV/résumé) from our database at any time and without providing any reason. Therefore, please retain your own copy of the personal information provided to Schrödinger.

 **What choices do I have regarding collection, use and distribution of my information?**

If you do not want to receive email or direct mail from Schrödinger, simply follow the directions contained in each such communication to remove your name from our mailing list. You may also contact us at [**remove@schrodinger.com**](mailto:remove@schrodinger.com).

We will try to comply with your request(s) as soon as reasonably practicable. Please also note that if you do opt-out of receiving marketing-related emails from us, we may still send you important administrative messages, and you cannot opt-out from receiving administrative messages.

 **What security measures does Schrödinger use to protect my information from loss, misuse or alteration?**

Certain pages on our Web Site use Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) encryption technology to encrypt the data submitted to our Web Site. The SSL protocol provides server authentication, data integrity, and privacy on the Web. Your web browser will usually indicate, with a “padlock” icon, or by a similar means, when the information that you are submitting to our Web Site is SSL-encrypted.

Whether or not it is encrypted, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, Schrödinger cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or from our Web Site, and therefore you use our Web Site at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we use our best effort to ensure its security on our systems.

As a global company, Schrödinger has sites and users all over the world. When you give Schrödinger personal information, that information may be sent electronically to servers outside of the country where you originally entered the information. In addition, that information may be used, stored and processed outside of the country where you entered that information. Whenever Schrödinger handles personal information, regardless of where this occurs, it takes steps to ensure that your information is treated securely and in accordance with the relevant Terms of Use and this privacy policy.

 **How can I correct or change or view my personal information?**

If you would like to view, correct, change or remove any personal information you have provided, please send e-mail to [**personal@schrodinger.com**](mailto:personal@schrodinger.com), contact us at IT Department, 120 West 45th Street, 17th Floor, New York, NY 10036.

In your request, please make clear what personal information you would like to have changed, whether you would like to have your personal information that you have provided to us suppressed from our database or otherwise let us know what limitations you would like to put on our use of your personal information that you have provided to us. For your protection, we may only implement requests with respect to the personal information associated with the particular email address that you use to send us your request, and we may need to verify your identity before implementing your request. We will try to comply with your request as soon as reasonably practicable.

Please note, however, that certain personal information may be exempt from such access, correction and deletion/suppression requests pursuant to applicable data protection laws or other laws and regulations. Also, please note that we may need to retain certain information for recordkeeping purposes, and that some residual information may remain within our databases and other records and will not be removed.

You may lodge a complaint about the way we process your personal information with a supervisory authority of your country or region.

 **What else should I know?**

This Web Site may contain links to various third-party Web sites. These sites may provide additional information, goods, services and/or promotions. These sites are owned and operated independently of Schrödinger and have their own separate privacy and data collection practices. Any information you provide to a third-party Web site will be governed by the terms (if any) of the privacy policy of such third-party Web site, and Schrödinger encourages you to review and understand the privacy practices of a third-party Web site before providing it with information. Schrödinger is not responsible for the content or policies of any third-party Web sites to which this Web Site links. SCHRÖDINGER EXPRESSLY DISCLAIMS ALL LIABILITY FOR THE CONTENT OR POLICIES OF ANY THIRD-PARTY WEB SITES TO WHICH THIS WEB SITE LINKS.

 **How can I contact Schrödinger?**

If you have questions or requests, please feel free to contact us at [personal@schrodinger.com](mailto:personal@schrodinger.com) or IT Department, 120 West 45th Street, 17th Floor, New York, NY 10036.

 \--

[日本語訳]

 **個人情報保護方針**

 **最終更新日：** **2011** **年** **6** **月** **12** **日**

シュレーディンガーは、プライバシーとセキュリティが多くの人々の関心事であることを認識しています。本個人情報保護方針は、シュレーディンガー LLCとその関連会社（以下「シュレーディンガー」または「弊社」といいます）における個人情報の収集、利用、開示、移転について説明するものです。

弊社に個人情報を提供する前に、本個人情報保護方針を注意深くお読みいただくようお願いいたします。シュレーディンガーは、本個人情報保護方針を随時修正する権利を有しており、変更した場合は、変更後の個人情報保護方針を本ウェブサイト（以下に定義します）に掲載いたします。

 **収集する個人情報について**

弊社は、お客様が弊社ウェブサイト上で入力した情報を含め、お客様が弊社に提供した情報をすべてお預かりし、保管します。「本ウェブサイト」とは、シュレーディンガーが運営または管理するすべてのウェブサイト（schrodinger.com、schrodinger.co.jp、PyMOL. orgを含みますが、これに限定されるものではありません）を指します（以下これらのウェブサイトを総称して、「本ウェブサイト」または「弊社ウェブサイト」といいます）。本ウェブサイトは、サイト訪問者が本ウェブサイト上で任意で提供した個人情報を収集します。典型的な例として、本ウェブサイト訪問者は、シュレーディンガーからサービスを受けるため、本サイト上に個人情報を提供する場合があります。例えば、本ウェブサイトでシュレーディンガーのソフトウエア製品の価格を照会したり、ログオン・アカウントの申し込みを新たに行ったり、シンポジウムやオンラインセミナー、キャンペーンに申し込んだり、本ウェブサイト上のリンクからシュレーディンガーに電子メールを送ろうとすると、氏名、役職、所属機関、住所、電子メールアドレス、その他連絡先など、個人情報の提供を求められます。ログオン・アカウントをお持ちのサイト訪問者も、シュレーディンガーのソフトウエアをダウンロードしたり、サポート資料を参照するなど、ご利用内容によってはコンテンツへのアクセスを許可するために電子メールアドレスやパスワードの入力をお願いしています。訪問者には、随時、任意の質問やアンケート調査への協力をお願いすることがあります。

お客様のコンピューターやインターネット・ブラウザに関する情報も、弊社ウェブサーバーやシュレーディンガーにウェブサイト分析サービスを提供する第三者のサーバーにより、自動的に収集されます。例えば、お客様のIPアドレス、ドメイン名、ブラウザの種類やバージョン、オペレーティング・システム、アクセスタイム、参照ウェブサイトのアドレスなどの情報が含まれます。弊社では、弊社ウェブページに「ウェブ・ビーコン」（「クリアGIF」とも呼ばれています）を埋め込み、これらの情報を収集しています。収集した情報は主に、本ウェブサイトの利用状況の把握（訪問者数、平均閲覧時間、閲覧ページなど）やウェブサイト改善のために利用しています。

 **クッキーについて**

多くのウェブサイトと同様、弊社ウェブサイトも基本的なウェブ機能を有効にするためにクッキーを利用しています。弊社ウェブサイトのクッキーは、訪問者のコンピューターのハードドライブまたはメモリーに情報を保存します。弊社ウェブサイトは、訪問者のブラウザに送信したクッキーを利用して、サイトの利用履歴に関する統計を作成し、ユーザーの嗜好を把握します。ログオン・アカウントをお持ちのお客様の場合、クッキーに保存された情報によりログイン名やパスワードを確認し、本ウェブサイト内のパスワードで保護された領域へのアクセスを許可します。

お客様はクッキーの受信について選択することができます。ご自分のブラウザの設定を変更すれば、クッキーをすべて受信したり、受信時の通知を表示させたり、すべての受信を拒否することができます。ただし、全てのクッキーの受信を拒否しますと、本ウェブサイトはお客様のログオン・アカウントを確認できないため、本ウェブサイト内のパスワードで保護された領域が利用できなくなります。本ウェブサイト上で個人情報を提供した場合、その情報はシュレーディンガーに提供されることになります。

 **個人情報の利用方法について**

シュレーディンガーは、お客様のアカウントの管理、当サイトへの登録や商品の注文、代金請求の手続き、お問い合わせやご要望への回答、シュレーディンガーのソフトウエアのサポート、ライセンシーやユーザーへのサポートのために個人情報を収集します。お客様から収集した情報は、新製品の開発や既存製品の改善、また、お客様への情報やアドバイスの提供、お勧め製品のご案内等に利用します。

また、収集した個人情報は、弊社および弊社関連会社、提携会社の製品やサービスに関する情報をお客様に提供するために利用することがあります。弊社および弊社関連会社、提携会社からお客様宛に電子メールやダイレクトメールが届くことがありますが、そうした情報を受け取りたくない場合、そのメール等に記載されている指示に従って配信停止の手続きを行うようお願いいたします。配信停止の手続きは電子メール（[remove@schrodinger.com](mailto:remove@schrodinger.com)）でも受け付けています。

さらに、シュレーディンガーは、収集した情報をもとに、ユーザー構成や興味の対象を調査することがあります。目的は、ユーザーについての理解を深め、サービス向上につなげることにあります。シュレーディンガーはこうしたデータを提携会社と共有することがあります。

 **個人情報の共有について**

シュレーディンガーは、シュレーディンガーの事業の管理と運営のために前述の目的および方法で、お客様の個人情報のすべての項目について関連会社と共有し、共同で利用します。関連会社には、Schrödinger, Inc.、Synaptic Science, LLC、シュレーディンガー株式会社が含まれますが、これらに限定されるものではありません。Schrödinger, Inc.は、その関連会社と共有・共同利用する個人情報の管理について責任を負うものとします。また、シュレーディンガーは、シュレーディンガーの委託先である外部サービスプロバイダーとお客様情報を共有することがありますが、その目的は、当該サービスプロバイダーがお客様のご要望に応えたり、シュレーディンガーに対して本個人情報保護方針の規定に沿ったサービスを提供したりできるようにするためです。

さらに、シュレーディンガーのシンポジウムやオンラインセミナーの参加申し込みをウェブ上で行った場合、参加者リストに記載される個人の連絡先はイベントのスポンサー（いる場合）と共有され、また、他の参加者とも共有される場合があります。そのため、イベント終了後、参加者のもとにはスポンサーなどから連絡が入ることがあります。

また、シュレーディンガーは、弊社ウェブサイトの利用規約に違反、またはシュレーディンガーもしくは他の者の権利を侵害する者、またはシュレーディンガーもしくは他の者の所有権を侵害する者を特定したり、その者に連絡を取ったり、法的措置を講じるために、個人情報を開示する必要があると判断できるなどの特別な場合、当該情報を開示することがあります。シュレーディンガーはまた、法律により要求または認められる場合、または法律の遵守、請求に対する対応、シュレーディンガーに送達された法的手続きの履行に必要であると善意で確信する場合、個人情報を開示したり、個人情報にアクセスすることがあります。個人情報の第三者への開示は、合併、買収、資金調達、会社資産売却の過程で行われることがあります。加えて、債務超過、破産、管財人による財産管理手続きの場合、個人情報がシュレーディンガーの事業資産の一部として、単一または複数の第三者に譲渡もしくは移転されることがあります。シュレーディンガーはまた、事業提携の交渉相手、広告主、その他の第三者に弊社ウェブサイトについて説明するため、またはその他の合法的な目的のために、ユーザーに関する集計ベースの統計を開示することがあります。

 **個人情報の収集、利用、配布について、お客様自身で選択できることがあります** ** **

シュレーディンガーから電子メールやダイレクトメールを受け取りたくない場合、そのメール等に記載されている指示に従って配信停止の手続きを行うようお願いいたします。配信停止の手続きは電子メール（[remove@schrodinger.com](mailto:remove@schrodinger.com)）でも受け付けています。

 **お客様情報の紛失、不正利用、改ざん防止のための安全対策について**

弊社ウェブサイトには、サイトに送信されたデータを暗号化するセキュア・ソケット・レイヤー（SSL）暗号化技術を利用したページがあります。SSLプロトコルは、サーバー認証、データの完全性、ウェブ上のプライバシーを提供します。お客様が弊社ウェブサイトに送信する情報がSSLで暗号化されている場合、通常、ブラウザには「鍵」のアイコン（または類似した表示）が現れます。

データが暗号化されても、インターネットでのデータ送信の安全性が100％保証されるわけではありません。したがって、弊社はお客様の個人情報の保護に鋭意努めておりますが、弊社ウェブサイトとお客様の間で送受信される情報の完全な安全性を保証することはできません。そのため、お客様には、ご自分でリスクを判断した上で、ウェブサイトのご利用をお願いいたします。お客様から情報を受け取った後は、弊社のシステムでその安全性が確保されるよう最善の努力をいたします。

シュレーディンガーは、グローバル企業として世界中にサイトとユーザーを有しています。シュレーディンガーに個人情報を提供されますと、その情報は情報を入力した国の外へ電子的方法によって送られることがあります。加えて、その情報は、それを入力した国の外で利用、保存、処理されることがあります。個人情報を扱うに際しては、扱う場所がどこであれ、シュレーディンガーはお客様の情報が安全かつ利用規約および本個人情報保護方針に従って扱われるよう対策を講じています。

 **個人情報の訂正、変更、閲覧の方法について**

お客様が提供された個人情報について、訂正、変更、閲覧をご希望の場合は、[personal@schrodinger.com](mailto:personal@schrodinger.com)に電子メールをお送りください。

 **その他の注意事項**

本ウェブサイトには、第三者のウェブサイトへのリンクが複数含まれていることがあります。これらのサイトにおいても、情報、製品、サービス、宣伝等が提供されていることがあります。これらのサイトはシュレーディンガーとは独立した所有者により運営されており、独自の個人情報保護方針やデータ収集の方法が採用されています。第三者のウェブサイトに情報を提供される場合は、その第三者ウェブサイトの個人情報保護方針の規定（ある場合）が適用されることになります。したがって、お客様は情報を提供される前に、その第三者のウェブサイトの個人情報保護方針をお読みいただき、内容を理解されるようお勧めいたします。シュレーディンガーは、本ウェブサイトのリンク先である第三者ウェブサイトのコンテンツや方針に対して責任を負うものではありません。 **本ウェブサイトのリンク先である第三者ウェブサイトのコンテンツまたは方針について、シュレーディンガーは一切の責任を明示的に否認いたします。**

\--

 **Privacy Policy - valid for European Citizens and Schrödinger GmbH**

We are very delighted that you have shown interest in our enterprise. Data protection is of a particularly high priority for the management of the Schrödinger GmbH. Our transparency document according to article 13 and 14 GDPR is available **[here](https://www.schrodinger.com/sites/default/files/final_art_13_und_14_eng.pdf)**.

The use of the Internet pages of the Schrödinger GmbH is possible without any indication of personal data; however, if a data subject wants to use special enterprise services via our website, processing of personal data could become necessary. If the processing of personal data is necessary and there is no statutory basis for such processing, we generally obtain consent from the data subject.

The processing of personal data, such as the name, address, e-mail address, or telephone number of a data subject shall always be in line with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), and in accordance with the country-specific data protection regulations applicable to the Schrödinger GmbH. By means of this data protection declaration, our enterprise would like to inform the general public of the nature, scope, and purpose of the personal data we collect, use and process. Furthermore, data subjects are informed, by means of this data protection declaration, of the rights to which they are entitled.

As the controller, the Schrödinger GmbH has implemented numerous technical and organizational measures to ensure the most complete protection of personal data processed through this website. However, Internet-based data transmissions may in principle have security gaps, so absolute protection may not be guaranteed. For this reason, every data subject is free to transfer personal data to us via alternative means, e.g. by telephone.

 **1\. Definitions**

The data protection declaration of the Schrödinger GmbH is based on the terms used by the European legislator for the adoption of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). Our data protection declaration should be legible and understandable for the general public, as well as our customers and business partners. To ensure this, we would like to first explain the terminology used.

In this data protection declaration, we use, inter alia, the following terms:

 **a) Personal data**

• Personal data means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person (“data subject”). An identifiable natural person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier or to one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of that natural person.

 **b) Data subject**

• Data subject is any identified or identifiable natural person, whose personal data is processed by the controller responsible for the processing.

 **c) Processing  **

• Processing is any operation or set of operations which is performed on personal data or on sets of personal data, whether or not by automated means, such as collection, recording, organisation, structuring, storage, adaptation or alteration, retrieval, consultation, use, disclosure by transmission, dissemination or otherwise making available, alignment or combination, restriction, erasure or destruction.

 **d) Restriction of processing**

• Restriction of processing is the marking of stored personal data with the aim of limiting their processing in the future.

 **e) Profiling**

• Profiling means any form of automated processing of personal data consisting of the use of personal data to evaluate certain personal aspects relating to a natural person, in particular to analyse or predict aspects concerning that natural person's performance at work, economic situation, health, personal preferences, interests, reliability, behaviour, location or movements.

 **f) Pseudonymisation**

• Pseudonymisation is the processing of personal data in such a manner that the personal data can no longer be attributed to a specific data subject without the use of additional information, provided that such additional information is kept separately and is subject to technical and organisational measures to ensure that the personal data are not attributed to an identified or identifiable natural person.

 **g) Controller or controller responsible for the processing**

• Controller or controller responsible for the processing is the natural or legal person, public authority, agency or other body which, alone or jointly with others, determines the purposes and means of the processing of personal data; where the purposes and means of such processing are determined by Union or Member State law, the controller or the specific criteria for its nomination may be provided for by Union or Member State law.

 **h) Processor**

• Processor is a natural or legal person, public authority, agency or other body which processes personal data on behalf of the controller.

 **i) Recipient**

• Recipient is a natural or legal person, public authority, agency or another body, to which the personal data are disclosed, whether a third party or not. However, public authorities which may receive personal data in the framework of a particular inquiry in accordance with Union or Member State law shall not be regarded as recipients; the processing of those data by those public authorities shall be in compliance with the applicable data protection rules according to the purposes of the processing.

 **j) Third party**

• Third party is a natural or legal person, public authority, agency or body other than the data subject, controller, processor and persons who, under the direct authority of the controller or processor, are authorised to process personal data.

 **k) Consent**

• Consent of the data subject is any freely given, specific, informed and unambiguous indication of the data subject's wishes by which he or she, by a statement or by a clear affirmative action, signifies agreement to the processing of personal data relating to him or her.

 **2\. Name and Address of the controller**

Controller for the purposes of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), other data protection laws applicable in Member states of the European Union and other provisions related to data protection is:

Schrödinger GmbH   
Q7, 23  
68161 Mannheim   
Deutschland   
Phone: +49 89 45 835464   
Email: [thomas.klott@schrodinger.com](mailto:thomas.klott@schrodinger.com)   
Website: [www.schrodinger.com](http://www.schrodinger.com/)

 **3\. Name and Address of the Data Protection Officer**

The Data Protection Officer of the controller is:

Heiko Jonny Maniero   
DGD Deutsche Gesellschaft für Datenschutz GmbH   
Robert-Bosch-Str. 11   
85221 Dachau   
Deutschland  
Phone: 08131-77987-0   
Email: [info@dg-datenschutz.de](mailto:info@dg-datenschutz.de)   
Website: [www.dg-datenschutz.de](http://www.dg-datenschutz.de/)

Any data subject may, at any time, contact our Data Protection Officer directly with all questions and suggestions concerning data protection.

 **4\. Cookies**

The Internet pages of the Schrödinger GmbH use cookies. Cookies are text files that are stored in a computer system via an Internet browser.

Many Internet sites and servers use cookies. Many cookies contain a so-called cookie ID. A cookie ID is a unique identifier of the cookie. It consists of a character string through which Internet pages and servers can be assigned to the specific Internet browser in which the cookie was stored. This allows visited Internet sites and servers to differentiate the individual browser of the data subject from other Internet browsers that contain other cookies. A specific Internet browser can be recognized and identified using the unique cookie ID.

Through the use of cookies, the Schrödinger GmbH can provide the users of this website with more user-friendly services that would not be possible without the cookie setting.

By means of a cookie, the information and offers on our website can be optimized with the user in mind. Cookies allow us, as previously mentioned, to recognize our website users. The purpose of this recognition is to make it easier for users to utilize our website. The website user that uses cookies, e.g. does not have to enter access data each time the website is accessed, because this is taken over by the website, and the cookie is thus stored on the user's computer system. Another example is the cookie of a shopping cart in an online shop. The online store remembers the articles that a customer has placed in the virtual shopping cart via a cookie.

The data subject may, at any time, prevent the setting of cookies through our website by means of a corresponding setting of the Internet browser used, and may thus permanently deny the setting of cookies. Furthermore, already set cookies may be deleted at any time via an Internet browser or other software programs. This is possible in all popular Internet browsers. If the data subject deactivates the setting of cookies in the Internet browser used, not all functions of our website may be entirely usable.

 **5\. Collection of general data and information**

The website of the Schrödinger GmbH collects a series of general data and information when a data subject or automated system calls up the website. This general data and information are stored in the server log files. Collected may be (1) the browser types and versions used, (2) the operating system used by the accessing system, (3) the website from which an accessing system reaches our website (so-called referrers), (4) the sub-websites, (5) the date and time of access to the Internet site, (6) an Internet protocol address (IP address), (7) the Internet service provider of the accessing system, and (8) any other similar data and information that may be used in the event of attacks on our information technology systems.

When using these general data and information, the Schrödinger GmbH does not draw any conclusions about the data subject. Rather, this information is needed to (1) deliver the content of our website correctly, (2) optimize the content of our website as well as its advertisement, (3) ensure the long-term viability of our information technology systems and website technology, and (4) provide law enforcement authorities with the information necessary for criminal prosecution in case of a cyber-attack. Therefore, the Schrödinger GmbH analyzes anonymously collected data and information statistically, with the aim of increasing the data protection and data security of our enterprise, and to ensure an optimal level of protection for the personal data we process. The anonymous data of the server log files are stored separately from all personal data provided by a data subject.

 **6\. Registration on our website**

The data subject has the possibility to register on the website of the controller with the indication of personal data. Which personal data are transmitted to the controller is determined by the respective input mask used for the registration. The personal data entered by the data subject are collected and stored exclusively for internal use by the controller, and for his own purposes. The controller may request transfer to one or more processors (e.g. a parcel service) that also uses personal data for an internal purpose which is attributable to the controller.

By registering on the website of the controller, the IP address—assigned by the Internet service provider (ISP) and used by the data subject—date, and time of the registration are also stored. The storage of this data takes place against the background that this is the only way to prevent the misuse of our services, and, if necessary, to make it possible to investigate committed offenses. Insofar, the storage of this data is necessary to secure the controller. This data is not passed on to third parties unless there is a statutory obligation to pass on the data, or if the transfer serves the aim of criminal prosecution.

The registration of the data subject, with the voluntary indication of personal data, is intended to enable the controller to offer the data subject contents or services that may only be offered to registered users due to the nature of the matter in question. Registered persons are free to change the personal data specified during the registration at any time, or to have them completely deleted from the data stock of the controller.

The data controller shall, at any time, provide information upon request to each data subject as to what personal data are stored about the data subject. In addition, the data controller shall correct or erase personal data at the request or indication of the data subject, insofar as there are no statutory storage obligations. The entirety of the controller’s employees are available to the data subject in this respect as contact persons.

 **7\. Subscription to our newsletters**

On the website of the Schrödinger GmbH, users are given the opportunity to subscribe to our enterprise's newsletter. The input mask used for this purpose determines what personal data are transmitted, as well as when the newsletter is ordered from the controller.

The Schrödinger GmbH informs its customers and business partners regularly by means of a newsletter about enterprise offers. The enterprise's newsletter may only be received by the data subject if (1) the data subject has a valid e-mail address and (2) the data subject registers for the newsletter shipping. A confirmation e-mail will be sent to the e-mail address registered by a data subject for the first time for newsletter shipping, for legal reasons, in the double opt-in procedure. This confirmation e-mail is used to prove whether the owner of the e-mail address as the data subject is authorized to receive the newsletter.

During the registration for the newsletter, we also store the IP address of the computer system assigned by the Internet service provider (ISP) and used by the data subject at the time of the registration, as well as the date and time of the registration. The collection of this data is necessary in order to understand the (possible) misuse of the e-mail address of a data subject at a later date, and it therefore serves the aim of the legal protection of the controller.

The personal data collected as part of a registration for the newsletter will only be used to send our newsletter. In addition, subscribers to the newsletter may be informed by e-mail, as long as this is necessary for the operation of the newsletter service or a registration in question, as this could be the case in the event of modifications to the newsletter offer, or in the event of a change in technical circumstances. There will be no transfer of personal data collected by the newsletter service to third parties. The subscription to our newsletter may be terminated by the data subject at any time. The consent to the storage of personal data, which the data subject has given for shipping the newsletter, may be revoked at any time. For the purpose of revocation of consent, a corresponding link is found in each newsletter. It is also possible to unsubscribe from the newsletter at any time directly on the website of the controller, or to communicate this to the controller in a different way.

 **8\. Newsletter-Tracking**

The newsletter of the Schrödinger GmbH contains so-called tracking pixels. A tracking pixel is a miniature graphic embedded in such e-mails, which are sent in HTML format to enable log file recording and analysis. This allows a statistical analysis of the success or failure of online marketing campaigns. Based on the embedded tracking pixel, the Schrödinger GmbH may see if and when an e-mail was opened by a data subject, and which links in the e-mail were called up by data subjects.

Such personal data collected in the tracking pixels contained in the newsletters are stored and analyzed by the controller in order to optimize the shipping of the newsletter, as well as to adapt the content of future newsletters even better to the interests of the data subject. These personal data will not be passed on to third parties. Data subjects are at any time entitled to revoke the respective separate declaration of consent issued by means of the double-opt-in procedure. After a revocation, these personal data will be deleted by the controller. The Schrödinger GmbH automatically regards a withdrawal from the receipt of the newsletter as a revocation.

 **9\. Routine erasure and blocking of personal data**

The data controller shall process and store the personal data of the data subject only for the period necessary to achieve the purpose of storage, or as far as this is granted by the European legislator or other legislators in laws or regulations to which the controller is subject to.

If the storage purpose is not applicable, or if a storage period prescribed by the European legislator or another competent legislator expires, the personal data are routinely blocked or erased in accordance with legal requirements.

 **10\. Rights of the data subject**

 **a) Right of confirmation**

• Each data subject shall have the right granted by the European legislator to obtain from the controller the confirmation as to whether or not personal data concerning him or her are being processed. If a data subject wishes to avail himself of this right of confirmation, he or she may, at any time, contact any employee of the controller.

 **b) Right of access**

• Each data subject shall have the right granted by the European legislator to obtain from the controller free information about his or her personal data stored at any time and a copy of this information. Furthermore, the European directives and regulations grant the data subject access to the following information:

o the purposes of the processing; o the categories of personal data concerned;  
o the recipients or categories of recipients to whom the personal data have been or will be disclosed, in particular recipients in third countries or international organisations;   
o where possible, the envisaged period for which the personal data will be stored, or, if not possible, the criteria used to determine that period;   
o the existence of the right to request from the controller rectification or erasure of personal data, or restriction of processing of personal data concerning the data subject, or to object to such processing;   
o the existence of the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority;   
o where the personal data are not collected from the data subject, any available information as to their source;   
o the existence of automated decision-making, including profiling, referred to in Article 22(1) and (4) of the GDPR and, at least in those cases, meaningful information about the logic involved, as well as the significance and envisaged consequences of such processing for the data subject.

• Furthermore, the data subject shall have a right to obtain information as to whether personal data are transferred to a third country or to an international organisation. Where this is the case, the data subject shall have the right to be informed of the appropriate safeguards relating to the transfer.

• If a data subject wishes to avail himself of this right of access, he or she may, at any time, contact any employee of the controller.

 **c) Right to rectification**

• Each data subject shall have the right granted by the European legislator to obtain from the controller without undue delay the rectification of inaccurate personal data concerning him or her. Taking into account the purposes of the processing, the data subject shall have the right to have incomplete personal data completed, including by means of providing a supplementary statement.

• If a data subject wishes to exercise this right to rectification, he or she may, at any time, contact any employee of the controller.

 **d) Right to erasure (Right to be forgotten)**

• Each data subject shall have the right granted by the European legislator to obtain from the controller the erasure of personal data concerning him or her without undue delay, and the controller shall have the obligation to erase personal data without undue delay where one of the following grounds applies, as long as the processing is not necessary:

o The personal data are no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which they were collected or otherwise processed.   
o The data subject withdraws consent to which the processing is based according to point (a) of Article 6(1) of the GDPR, or point (a) of Article 9(2) of the GDPR, and where there is no other legal ground for the processing.   
o The data subject objects to the processing pursuant to Article 21(1) of the GDPR and there are no overriding legitimate grounds for the processing, or the data subject objects to the processing pursuant to Article 21(2) of the GDPR.   
o The personal data have been unlawfully processed. o The personal data must be erased for compliance with a legal obligation in Union or Member State law to which the controller is subject.   
o The personal data have been collected in relation to the offer of information society services referred to in Article 8(1) of the GDPR.

• If one of the aforementioned reasons applies, and a data subject wishes to request the erasure of personal data stored by the Schrödinger GmbH, he or she may, at any time, contact any employee of the controller. An employee of Schrödinger GmbH shall promptly ensure that the erasure request is complied with immediately.

• Where the controller has made personal data public and is obliged pursuant to Article 17(1) to erase the personal data, the controller, taking account of available technology and the cost of implementation, shall take reasonable steps, including technical measures, to inform other controllers processing the personal data that the data subject has requested erasure by such controllers of any links to, or copy or replication of, those personal data, as far as processing is not required. An employees of the Schrödinger GmbH will arrange the necessary measures in individual cases.

 **e) Right of restriction of processing**

• Each data subject shall have the right granted by the European legislator to obtain from the controller restriction of processing where one of the following applies

o The accuracy of the personal data is contested by the data subject, for a period enabling the controller to verify the accuracy of the personal data.  
o The processing is unlawful and the data subject opposes the erasure of the personal data and requests instead the restriction of their use instead.   
o The controller no longer needs the personal data for the purposes of the processing, but they are required by the data subject for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.  
o The data subject has objected to processing pursuant to Article 21(1) of the GDPR pending the verification whether the legitimate grounds of the controller override those of the data subject.

• If one of the aforementioned conditions is met, and a data subject wishes to request the restriction of the processing of personal data stored by the Schrödinger GmbH, he or she may at any time contact any employee of the controller. The employee of the Schrödinger GmbH will arrange the restriction of the processing.

 **f) Right to data portability**

• Each data subject shall have the right granted by the European legislator, to receive the personal data concerning him or her, which was provided to a controller, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. He or she shall have the right to transmit those data to another controller without hindrance from the controller to which the personal data have been provided, as long as the processing is based on consent pursuant to point (a) of Article 6(1) of the GDPR or point (a) of Article 9(2) of the GDPR, or on a contract pursuant to point (b) of Article 6(1) of the GDPR, and the processing is carried out by automated means, as long as the processing is not necessary for the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in the controller.

• Furthermore, in exercising his or her right to data portability pursuant to Article 20(1) of the GDPR, the data subject shall have the right to have personal data transmitted directly from one controller to another, where technically feasible and when doing so does not adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others.

• In order to assert the right to data portability, the data subject may at any time contact any employee of the Schrödinger GmbH.

 **g) Right to object**

• Each data subject shall have the right granted by the European legislator to object, on grounds relating to his or her particular situation, at any time, to processing of personal data concerning him or her, which is based on point (e) or (f) of Article 6(1) of the GDPR. This also applies to profiling based on these provisions.

• The Schrödinger GmbH shall no longer process the personal data in the event of the objection, unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override the interests, rights and freedoms of the data subject, or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

• If the Schrödinger GmbH processes personal data for direct marketing purposes, the data subject shall have the right to object at any time to processing of personal data concerning him or her for such marketing. This applies to profiling to the extent that it is related to such direct marketing. If the data subject objects to the Schrödinger GmbH to the processing for direct marketing purposes, the Schrödinger GmbH will no longer process the personal data for these purposes.

• In addition, the data subject has the right, on grounds relating to his or her particular situation, to object to processing of personal data concerning him or her by the Schrödinger GmbH for scientific or historical research purposes, or for statistical purposes pursuant to Article 89(1) of the GDPR, unless the processing is necessary for the performance of a task carried out for reasons of public interest.

• In order to exercise the right to object, the data subject may contact any employee of the Schrödinger GmbH. In addition, the data subject is free in the context of the use of information society services, and notwithstanding Directive 2002/58/EC, to use his or her right to object by automated means using technical specifications.

 **h) Automated individual decision-making, including profiling**

• Each data subject shall have the right granted by the European legislator not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing, including profiling, which produces legal effects concerning him or her, or similarly significantly affects him or her, as long as the decision (1) is not is necessary for entering into, or the performance of, a contract between the data subject and a data controller, or (2) is not authorised by Union or Member State law to which the controller is subject and which also lays down suitable measures to safeguard the data subject's rights and freedoms and legitimate interests, or (3) is not based on the data subject's explicit consent.

• If the decision (1) is necessary for entering into, or the performance of, a contract between the data subject and a data controller, or (2) it is based on the data subject's explicit consent, the Schrödinger GmbH shall implement suitable measures to safeguard the data subject's rights and freedoms and legitimate interests, at least the right to obtain human intervention on the part of the controller, to express his or her point of view and contest the decision.

• If the data subject wishes to exercise the rights concerning automated individual decision-making, he or she may, at any time, contact any employee of the Schrödinger GmbH.

 **i) Right to withdraw data protection consent**

• Each data subject shall have the right granted by the European legislator to withdraw his or her consent to processing of his or her personal data at any time.

• If the data subject wishes to exercise the right to withdraw the consent, he or she may, at any time, contact any employee of the Schrödinger GmbH.

 **11\. Data protection for applications and the application procedures**

The data controller shall collect and process the personal data of applicants for the purpose of the processing of the application procedure. The processing may also be carried out electronically. This is the case, in particular, if an applicant submits corresponding application documents by e-mail or by means of a web form on the website to the controller. If the data controller concludes an employment contract with an applicant, the submitted data will be stored for the purpose of processing the employment relationship in compliance with legal requirements. If no employment contract is concluded with the applicant by the controller, the application documents shall be automatically erased two months after notification of the refusal decision, provided that no other legitimate interests of the controller are opposed to the erasure. Other legitimate interest in this relation is, e.g. a burden of proof in a procedure under the General Equal Treatment Act (AGG).

 **12\. Data protection provisions about the application and use of Google Analytics (with anonymization function)**

On this website, the controller has integrated the component of Google Analytics (with the anonymizer function). Google Analytics is a web analytics service. Web analytics is the collection, gathering, and analysis of data about the behavior of visitors to websites. A web analysis service collects, inter alia, data about the website from which a person has come (the so-called referrer), which sub-pages were visited, or how often and for what duration a sub-page was viewed. Web analytics are mainly used for the optimization of a website and in order to carry out a cost-benefit analysis of Internet advertising.

The operator of the Google Analytics component is Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Pkwy, Mountain View, CA 94043-1351, United States.

For the web analytics through Google Analytics the controller uses the application "_gat. _anonymizeIp". By means of this application the IP address of the Internet connection of the data subject is abridged by Google and anonymised when accessing our websites from a Member State of the European Union or another Contracting State to the Agreement on the European Economic Area.

The purpose of the Google Analytics component is to analyze the traffic on our website. Google uses the collected data and information, inter alia, to evaluate the use of our website and to provide online reports, which show the activities on our websites, and to provide other services concerning the use of our Internet site for us.

Google Analytics places a cookie on the information technology system of the data subject. The definition of cookies is explained above. With the setting of the cookie, Google is enabled to analyze the use of our website. With each call-up to one of the individual pages of this Internet site, which is operated by the controller and into which a Google Analytics component was integrated, the Internet browser on the information technology system of the data subject will automatically submit data through the Google Analytics component for the purpose of online advertising and the settlement of commissions to Google. During the course of this technical procedure, the enterprise Google gains knowledge of personal information, such as the IP address of the data subject, which serves Google, inter alia, to understand the origin of visitors and clicks, and subsequently create commission settlements.

The cookie is used to store personal information, such as the access time, the location from which the access was made, and the frequency of visits of our website by the data subject. With each visit to our Internet site, such personal data, including the IP address of the Internet access used by the data subject, will be transmitted to Google in the United States of America. These personal data are stored by Google in the United States of America. Google may pass these personal data collected through the technical procedure to third parties.

The data subject may, as stated above, prevent the setting of cookies through our website at any time by means of a corresponding adjustment of the web browser used and thus permanently deny the setting of cookies. Such an adjustment to the Internet browser used would also prevent Google Analytics from setting a cookie on the information technology system of the data subject.

In addition, cookies already in use by Google Analytics may be deleted at any time via a web browser or other software programs. In addition, the data subject has the possibility of objecting to a collection of data that are generated by Google Analytics, which is related to the use of this website, as well as the processing of this data by Google and the chance to preclude any such. For this purpose, the data subject must download a browser add-on under the link <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout> and install it. This browser add-on tells Google Analytics through a JavaScript, that any data and information about the visits of Internet pages may not be transmitted to Google Analytics. The installation of the browser add-ons is considered an objection by Google. If the information technology system of the data subject is later deleted, formatted, or newly installed, then the data subject must reinstall the browser add-ons to disable Google Analytics. If the browser add-on was uninstalled by the data subject or any other person who is attributable to their sphere of competence, or is disabled, it is possible to execute the reinstallation or reactivation of the browser add-ons.

Further information and the applicable data protection provisions of Google may be retrieved under <https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/> and under <http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html>. Google Analytics is further explained under the following Link <https://www.google.com/analytics/>.

 **13\. Data protection provisions about the application and use of Google+**

On this website, the controller has integrated the Google+ button as a component. Google+ is a so-called social network. A social network is a social meeting place on the Internet, an online community, which usually allows users to communicate with each other and interact in a virtual space. A social network may serve as a platform for the exchange of opinions and experiences, or enable the Internet community to provide personal or business-related information. Google+ allows users of the social network to include the creation of private profiles, upload photos and network through friend requests.

The operating company of Google+ is Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Pkwy, Mountain View, CA 94043-1351, UNITED STATES.

With each call-up to one of the individual pages of this website, which is operated by the controller and on which a Google+ button has been integrated, the Internet browser on the information technology system of the data subject automatically downloads a display of the corresponding Google+ button of Google through the respective Google+ button component. During the course of this technical procedure, Google is made aware of what specific sub-page of our website was visited by the data subject. More detailed information about Google+ is available under <https://developers.google.com/+/>.

If the data subject is logged in at the same time to Google+, Google recognizes with each call-up to our website by the data subject and for the entire duration of his or her stay on our Internet site, which specific sub-pages of our Internet page were visited by the data subject. This information is collected through the Google+ button and Google matches this with the respective Google+ account associated with the data subject.

If the data subject clicks on the Google+ button integrated on our website and thus gives a Google+ 1 recommendation, then Google assigns this information to the personal Google+ user account of the data subject and stores the personal data. Google stores the Google+ 1 recommendation of the data subject, making it publicly available in accordance with the terms and conditions accepted by the data subject in this regard. Subsequently, a Google+ 1 recommendation given by the data subject on this website together with other personal data, such as the Google+ account name used by the data subject and the stored photo, is stored and processed on other Google services, such as search-engine results of the Google search engine, the Google account of the data subject or in other places, e.g. on Internet pages, or in relation to advertisements. Google is also able to link the visit to this website with other personal data stored on Google. Google further records this personal information with the purpose of improving or optimizing the various Google services.

Through the Google+ button, Google receives information that the data subject visited our website, if the data subject at the time of the call-up to our website is logged in to Google+. This occurs regardless of whether the data subject clicks or doesn’t click on the Google+ button.

If the data subject does not wish to transmit personal data to Google, he or she may prevent such transmission by logging out of his Google+ account before calling up our website.

Further information and the data protection provisions of Google may be retrieved under <https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>. More references from Google about the Google+ 1 button may be obtained under <https://developers.google.com/+/web/buttons-policy>.

 **14\. Data protection provisions about the application and use of LinkedIn**

The controller has integrated components of the LinkedIn Corporation on this website. LinkedIn is a web-based social network that enables users with existing business contacts to connect and to make new business contacts. Over 400 million registered people in more than 200 countries use LinkedIn. Thus, LinkedIn is currently the largest platform for business contacts and one of the most visited websites in the world.

The operating company of LinkedIn is LinkedIn Corporation, 2029 Stierlin Court Mountain View, CA 94043, UNITED STATES. For privacy matters outside of the UNITED STATES LinkedIn Ireland, Privacy Policy Issues, Wilton Plaza, Wilton Place, Dublin 2, Ireland, is responsible.

With each call-up to one of the individual pages of this Internet site, which is operated by the controller and on which a LinkedIn component (LinkedIn plug-in) was integrated, the Internet browser on the information technology system of the data subject is automatically prompted to the download of a display of the corresponding LinkedIn component of LinkedIn. Further information about the LinkedIn plug-in may be accessed under <https://developer.linkedin.com/plugins>. During the course of this technical procedure, LinkedIn gains knowledge of what specific sub-page of our website was visited by the data subject.

If the data subject is logged in at the same time on LinkedIn, LinkedIn detects with every call-up to our website by the data subject—and for the entire duration of their stay on our Internet site—which specific sub-page of our Internet page was visited by the data subject. This information is collected through the LinkedIn component and associated with the respective LinkedIn account of the data subject. If the data subject clicks on one of the LinkedIn buttons integrated on our website, then LinkedIn assigns this information to the personal LinkedIn user account of the data subject and stores the personal data.

LinkedIn receives information via the LinkedIn component that the data subject has visited our website, provided that the data subject is logged in at LinkedIn at the time of the call-up to our website. This occurs regardless of whether the person clicks on the LinkedIn button or not. If such a transmission of information to LinkedIn is not desirable for the data subject, then he or she may prevent this by logging off from their LinkedIn account before a call-up to our website is made.

LinkedIn provides under <https://www.linkedin.com/psettings/guest-controls> the possibility to unsubscribe from e-mail messages, SMS messages and targeted ads, as well as the ability to manage ad settings. LinkedIn also uses affiliates such as Eire, Google Analytics, BlueKai, DoubleClick, Nielsen, Comscore, Eloqua, and Lotame. The setting of such cookies may be denied under <https://www.linkedin.com/legal/cookie-policy>. The applicable privacy policy for LinkedIn is available under <https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy>. The LinkedIn Cookie Policy is available under <https://www.linkedin.com/legal/cookie-policy>.

 **15\. Data protection provisions about the application and use of Twitter**

On this website, the controller has integrated components of Twitter. Twitter is a multilingual, publicly-accessible microblogging service on which users may publish and spread so-called ‘tweets,’ e.g. short messages, which are limited to 280 characters. These short messages are available for everyone, including those who are not logged on to Twitter. The tweets are also displayed to so-called followers of the respective user. Followers are other Twitter users who follow a user's tweets. Furthermore, Twitter allows you to address a wide audience via hashtags, links or retweets.

The operating company of Twitter is Twitter, Inc., 1355 Market Street, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, UNITED STATES.

With each call-up to one of the individual pages of this Internet site, which is operated by the controller and on which a Twitter component (Twitter button) was integrated, the Internet browser on the information technology system of the data subject is automatically prompted to download a display of the corresponding Twitter component of Twitter. Further information about the Twitter buttons is available under <https://about.twitter.com/de/resources/buttons>. During the course of this technical procedure, Twitter gains knowledge of what specific sub-page of our website was visited by the data subject. The purpose of the integration of the Twitter component is a retransmission of the contents of this website to allow our users to introduce this web page to the digital world and increase our visitor numbers.

If the data subject is logged in at the same time on Twitter, Twitter detects with every call-up to our website by the data subject and for the entire duration of their stay on our Internet site which specific sub-page of our Internet page was visited by the data subject. This information is collected through the Twitter component and associated with the respective Twitter account of the data subject. If the data subject clicks on one of the Twitter buttons integrated on our website, then Twitter assigns this information to the personal Twitter user account of the data subject and stores the personal data.

Twitter receives information via the Twitter component that the data subject has visited our website, provided that the data subject is logged in on Twitter at the time of the call-up to our website. This occurs regardless of whether the person clicks on the Twitter component or not. If such a transmission of information to Twitter is not desirable for the data subject, then he or she may prevent this by logging off from their Twitter account before a call-up to our website is made.

The applicable data protection provisions of Twitter may be accessed under <https://twitter.com/privacy?lang=en>.

 **16\. Data protection provisions about the application and use of YouTube**

On this website, the controller has integrated components of YouTube. YouTube is an Internet video portal that enables video publishers to set video clips and other users free of charge, which also provides free viewing, review and commenting on them. YouTube allows you to publish all kinds of videos, so you can access both full movies and TV broadcasts, as well as music videos, trailers, and videos made by users via the Internet portal.

The operating company of YouTube is YouTube, LLC, 901 Cherry Ave., San Bruno, CA 94066, UNITED STATES. The YouTube, LLC is a subsidiary of Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Pkwy, Mountain View, CA 94043-1351, UNITED STATES.

With each call-up to one of the individual pages of this Internet site, which is operated by the controller and on which a YouTube component (YouTube video) was integrated, the Internet browser on the information technology system of the data subject is automatically prompted to download a display of the corresponding YouTube component. Further information about YouTube may be obtained under <https://www.youtube.com/about/en/>. During the course of this technical procedure, YouTube and Google gain knowledge of what specific sub-page of our website was visited by the data subject.

If the data subject is logged in on YouTube, YouTube recognizes with each call-up to a sub-page that contains a YouTube video, which specific sub-page of our Internet site was visited by the data subject. This information is collected by YouTube and Google and assigned to the respective YouTube account of the data subject.

YouTube and Google will receive information through the YouTube component that the data subject has visited our website, if the data subject at the time of the call to our website is logged in on YouTube; this occurs regardless of whether the person clicks on a YouTube video or not. If such a transmission of this information to YouTube and Google is not desirable for the data subject, the delivery may be prevented if the data subject logs off from their own YouTube account before a call-up to our website is made.

YouTube's data protection provisions, available at <https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>, provide information about the collection, processing and use of personal data by YouTube and Google.

 **17\. Legal basis for the processing**

Art. 6(1) lit. a GDPR serves as the legal basis for processing operations for which we obtain consent for a specific processing purpose. If the processing of personal data is necessary for the performance of a contract to which the data subject is party, as is the case, for example, when processing operations are necessary for the supply of goods or to provide any other service, the processing is based on Article 6(1) lit. b GDPR. The same applies to such processing operations which are necessary for carrying out pre-contractual measures, for example in the case of inquiries concerning our products or services. Is our company subject to a legal obligation by which processing of personal data is required, such as for the fulfillment of tax obligations, the processing is based on Art. 6(1) lit. c GDPR. In rare cases, the processing of personal data may be necessary to protect the vital interests of the data subject or of another natural person. This would be the case, for example, if a visitor were injured in our company and his name, age, health insurance data or other vital information would have to be passed on to a doctor, hospital or other third party. Then the processing would be based on Art. 6(1) lit. d GDPR. Finally, processing operations could be based on Article 6(1) lit. f GDPR. This legal basis is used for processing operations which are not covered by any of the abovementioned legal grounds, if processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by our company or by a third party, except where such interests are overridden by the interests or fundamental rights and freedoms of the data subject which require protection of personal data. Such processing operations are particularly permissible because they have been specifically mentioned by the European legislator. He considered that a legitimate interest could be assumed if the data subject is a client of the controller (Recital 47 Sentence 2 GDPR).

 **18\. The legitimate interests pursued by the controller or by a third party**

Where the processing of personal data is based on Article 6(1) lit. f GDPR our legitimate interest is to carry out our business in favor of the well-being of all our employees and the shareholders.

 **19\. Period for which the personal data will be stored**

The criteria used to determine the period of storage of personal data is the respective statutory retention period. After expiration of that period, the corresponding data is routinely deleted, as long as it is no longer necessary for the fulfillment of the contract or the initiation of a contract.

 **20\. Provision of personal data as statutory or contractual requirement; Requirement necessary to enter into a contract; Obligation of the data subject to provide the personal data; possible consequences of failure to provide such data**

We clarify that the provision of personal data is partly required by law (e.g. tax regulations) or can also result from contractual provisions (e.g. information on the contractual partner). Sometimes it may be necessary to conclude a contract that the data subject provides us with personal data, which must subsequently be processed by us. The data subject is, for example, obliged to provide us with personal data when our company signs a contract with him or her. The non-provision of the personal data would have the consequence that the contract with the data subject could not be concluded. Before personal data is provided by the data subject, the data subject must contact any employee. The employee clarifies to the data subject whether the provision of the personal data is required by law or contract or is necessary for the conclusion of the contract, whether there is an obligation to provide the personal data and the consequences of non-provision of the personal data.

 **21\. Existence of automated decision-making**

As a responsible company, we do not use automatic decision-making or profiling.

 **22\. Payment Method: Data protection provisions about the use of PayPal as a payment processor**

On this website, the controller has integrated components of PayPal. PayPal is an online payment service provider. Payments are processed via so-called PayPal accounts, which represent virtual private or business accounts. PayPal is also able to process virtual payments through credit cards when a user does not have a PayPal account. A PayPal account is managed via an e-mail address, which is why there are no classic account numbers. PayPal makes it possible to trigger online payments to third parties or to receive payments. PayPal also accepts trustee functions and offers buyer protection services.

The European operating company of PayPal is PayPal (Europe) S.à.r.l. & Cie. S.C.A., 22-24 Boulevard Royal, 2449 Luxembourg, Luxembourg.

If the data subject chooses "PayPal" as the payment option in the online shop during the ordering process, we automatically transmit the data of the data subject to PayPal. By selecting this payment option, the data subject agrees to the transfer of personal data required for payment processing.

The personal data transmitted to PayPal is usually first name, last name, address, email address, IP address, telephone number, mobile phone number, or other data necessary for payment processing. The processing of the purchase contract also requires such personal data, which are in connection with the respective order.

The transmission of the data is aimed at payment processing and fraud prevention. The controller will transfer personal data to PayPal, in particular, if a legitimate interest in the transmission is given. The personal data exchanged between PayPal and the controller for the processing of the data will be transmitted by PayPal to economic credit agencies. This transmission is intended for identity and creditworthiness checks. PayPal will, if necessary, pass on personal data to affiliates and service providers or subcontractors to the extent that this is necessary to fulfill contractual obligations or for data to be processed in the order.

The data subject has the possibility to revoke consent for the handling of personal data at any time from PayPal. A revocation shall not have any effect on personal data which must be processed, used or transmitted in accordance with (contractual) payment processing.

The applicable data protection provisions of PayPal may be retrieved under <https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full>.

\--

 **Privacy Policy - valid for European Citizens and Schrödinger, Inc.**

We are very delighted that you have shown interest in our enterprise. Data protection is of a particularly high priority for the management of the Schrödinger, Inc.. Our transparency document according to article 13 and 14 GDPR is available **[here](https://www.schrodinger.com/sites/default/files/inc_final_art_13_und_14_eng.pdf)**.

The use of the Internet pages of the Schrödinger, Inc. is possible without any indication of personal data; however, if a data subject wants to use special enterprise services via our website, processing of personal data could become necessary. If the processing of personal data is necessary and there is no statutory basis for such processing, we generally obtain consent from the data subject.

The processing of personal data, such as the name, address, e-mail address, or telephone number of a data subject shall always be in line with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), and in accordance with the country-specific data protection regulations applicable to the Schrödinger, Inc.. By means of this data protection declaration, our enterprise would like to inform the general public of the nature, scope, and purpose of the personal data we collect, use and process. Furthermore, data subjects are informed, by means of this data protection declaration, of the rights to which they are entitled.

As the controller, the Schrödinger, Inc. has implemented numerous technical and organizational measures to ensure the most complete protection of personal data processed through this website. However, Internet-based data transmissions may in principle have security gaps, so absolute protection may not be guaranteed. For this reason, every data subject is free to transfer personal data to us via alternative means, e.g. by telephone.

 **1\. Definitions**

The data protection declaration of the Schrödinger, Inc. is based on the terms used by the European legislator for the adoption of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). Our data protection declaration should be legible and understandable for the general public, as well as our customers and business partners. To ensure this, we would like to first explain the terminology used.

In this data protection declaration, we use, inter alia, the following terms:

 **a) Personal data**

• Personal data means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person (“data subject”). An identifiable natural person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier or to one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of that natural person.

 **b) Data subject**

• Data subject is any identified or identifiable natural person, whose personal data is processed by the controller responsible for the processing.

 **c) Processing**

• Processing is any operation or set of operations which is performed on personal data or on sets of personal data, whether or not by automated means, such as collection, recording, organisation, structuring, storage, adaptation or alteration, retrieval, consultation, use, disclosure by transmission, dissemination or otherwise making available, alignment or combination, restriction, erasure or destruction.

 **d) Restriction of processing**

• Restriction of processing is the marking of stored personal data with the aim of limiting their processing in the future.

 **e) Profiling**

• Profiling means any form of automated processing of personal data consisting of the use of personal data to evaluate certain personal aspects relating to a natural person, in particular to analyse or predict aspects concerning that natural person's performance at work, economic situation, health, personal preferences, interests, reliability, behaviour, location or movements.

 **f) Pseudonymisation**

• Pseudonymisation is the processing of personal data in such a manner that the personal data can no longer be attributed to a specific data subject without the use of additional information, provided that such additional information is kept separately and is subject to technical and organisational measures to ensure that the personal data are not attributed to an identified or identifiable natural person.

 **g) Controller or controller responsible for the processing**

• Controller or controller responsible for the processing is the natural or legal person, public authority, agency or other body which, alone or jointly with others, determines the purposes and means of the processing of personal data; where the purposes and means of such processing are determined by Union or Member State law, the controller or the specific criteria for its nomination may be provided for by Union or Member State law. • h) Processor • Processor is a natural or legal person, public authority, agency or other body which processes personal data on behalf of the controller.

 **i) Recipient**

• Recipient is a natural or legal person, public authority, agency or another body, to which the personal data are disclosed, whether a third party or not. However, public authorities which may receive personal data in the framework of a particular inquiry in accordance with Union or Member State law shall not be regarded as recipients; the processing of those data by those public authorities shall be in compliance with the applicable data protection rules according to the purposes of the processing.

 **  j) Third party**

• Third party is a natural or legal person, public authority, agency or body other than the data subject, controller, processor and persons who, under the direct authority of the controller or processor, are authorised to process personal data.

 **k) Consent**

• Consent of the data subject is any freely given, specific, informed and unambiguous indication of the data subject's wishes by which he or she, by a statement or by a clear affirmative action, signifies agreement to the processing of personal data relating to him or her.

 **2\. Name and Address of the controller**

Controller for the purposes of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), other data protection laws applicable in Member states of the European Union and other provisions related to data protection is:

Schrödinger, Inc. 120 WEST 45TH STREET 17TH FLOOR NEW YORK NY-10036 Email: [personal@schrodinger.com](mailto:personal@schrodinger.com) Website: [www.schrodinger.com](http://www.schrodinger.com/)

 **3\. Cookies**

The Internet pages of the Schrödinger, Inc. use cookies. Cookies are text files that are stored in a computer system via an Internet browser.

Many Internet sites and servers use cookies. Many cookies contain a so-called cookie ID. A cookie ID is a unique identifier of the cookie. It consists of a character string through which Internet pages and servers can be assigned to the specific Internet browser in which the cookie was stored. This allows visited Internet sites and servers to differentiate the individual browser of the dats subject from other Internet browsers that contain other cookies. A specific Internet browser can be recognized and identified using the unique cookie ID.

Through the use of cookies, the Schrödinger, Inc. can provide the users of this website with more user-friendly services that would not be possible without the cookie setting.

By means of a cookie, the information and offers on our website can be optimized with the user in mind. Cookies allow us, as previously mentioned, to recognize our website users. The purpose of this recognition is to make it easier for users to utilize our website. The website user that uses cookies, e.g. does not have to enter access data each time the website is accessed, because this is taken over by the website, and the cookie is thus stored on the user's computer system. Another example is the cookie of a shopping cart in an online shop. The online store remembers the articles that a customer has placed in the virtual shopping cart via a cookie.

The data subject may, at any time, prevent the setting of cookies through our website by means of a corresponding setting of the Internet browser used, and may thus permanently deny the setting of cookies. Furthermore, already set cookies may be deleted at any time via an Internet browser or other software programs. This is possible in all popular Internet browsers. If the data subject deactivates the setting of cookies in the Internet browser used, not all functions of our website may be entirely usable.

 **4\. Collection of general data and information**

The website of the Schrödinger, Inc. collects a series of general data and information when a data subject or automated system calls up the website. This general data and information are stored in the server log files. Collected may be (1) the browser types and versions used, (2) the operating system used by the accessing system, (3) the website from which an accessing system reaches our website (so-called referrers), (4) the sub-websites, (5) the date and time of access to the Internet site, (6) an Internet protocol address (IP address), (7) the Internet service provider of the accessing system, and (8) any other similar data and information that may be used in the event of attacks on our information technology systems.

When using these general data and information, the Schrödinger, Inc. does not draw any conclusions about the data subject. Rather, this information is needed to (1) deliver the content of our website correctly, (2) optimize the content of our website as well as its advertisement, (3) ensure the long-term viability of our information technology systems and website technology, and (4) provide law enforcement authorities with the information necessary for criminal prosecution in case of a cyber-attack. Therefore, the Schrödinger, Inc. analyzes anonymously collected data and information statistically, with the aim of increasing the data protection and data security of our enterprise, and to ensure an optimal level of protection for the personal data we process. The anonymous data of the server log files are stored separately from all personal data provided by a data subject.

 **5\. Registration on our website**

The data subject has the possibility to register on the website of the controller with the indication of personal data. Which personal data are transmitted to the controller is determined by the respective input mask used for the registration. The personal data entered by the data subject are collected and stored exclusively for internal use by the controller, and for his own purposes. The controller may request transfer to one or more processors (e.g. a parcel service) that also uses personal data for an internal purpose which is attributable to the controller.

By registering on the website of the controller, the IP address—assigned by the Internet service provider (ISP) and used by the data subject—date, and time of the registration are also stored. The storage of this data takes place against the background that this is the only way to prevent the misuse of our services, and, if necessary, to make it possible to investigate committed offenses. Insofar, the storage of this data is necessary to secure the controller. This data is not passed on to third parties unless there is a statutory obligation to pass on the data, or if the transfer serves the aim of criminal prosecution.

The registration of the data subject, with the voluntary indication of personal data, is intended to enable the controller to offer the data subject contents or services that may only be offered to registered users due to the nature of the matter in question. Registered persons are free to change the personal data specified during the registration at any time, or to have them completely deleted from the data stock of the controller. The data controller shall, at any time, provide information upon request to each data subject as to what personal data are stored about the data subject. In addition, the data controller shall correct or erase personal data at the request or indication of the data subject, insofar as there are no statutory storage obligations. The entirety of the controller’s employees are available to the data subject in this respect as contact persons.

 **6\. Subscription to our newsletters**

On the website of the Schrödinger, Inc., users are given the opportunity to subscribe to our enterprise's newsletter. The input mask used for this purpose determines what personal data are transmitted, as well as when the newsletter is ordered from the controller.

The Schrödinger, Inc. informs its customers and business partners regularly by means of a newsletter about enterprise offers. The enterprise's newsletter may only be received by the data subject if (1) the data subject has a valid e-mail address and (2) the data subject registers for the newsletter shipping. A confirmation e-mail will be sent to the e-mail address registered by a data subject for the first time for newsletter shipping, for legal reasons, in the double opt-in procedure. This confirmation e-mail is used to prove whether the owner of the e-mail address as the data subject is authorized to receive the newsletter.

During the registration for the newsletter, we also store the IP address of the computer system assigned by the Internet service provider (ISP) and used by the data subject at the time of the registration, as well as the date and time of the registration. The collection of this data is necessary in order to understand the (possible) misuse of the e-mail address of a data subject at a later date, and it therefore serves the aim of the legal protection of the controller.

The personal data collected as part of a registration for the newsletter will only be used to send our newsletter. In addition, subscribers to the newsletter may be informed by e-mail, as long as this is necessary for the operation of the newsletter service or a registration in question, as this could be the case in the event of modifications to the newsletter offer, or in the event of a change in technical circumstances. There will be no transfer of personal data collected by the newsletter service to third parties. The subscription to our newsletter may be terminated by the data subject at any time. The consent to the storage of personal data, which the data subject has given for shipping the newsletter, may be revoked at any time. For the purpose of revocation of consent, a corresponding link is found in each newsletter. It is also possible to unsubscribe from the newsletter at any time directly on the website of the controller, or to communicate this to the controller in a different way.

 **7\. Newsletter-Tracking**

The newsletter of the Schrödinger, Inc. contains so-called tracking pixels. A tracking pixel is a miniature graphic embedded in such e-mails, which are sent in HTML format to enable log file recording and analysis. This allows a statistical analysis of the success or failure of online marketing campaigns. Based on the embedded tracking pixel, the Schrödinger, Inc. may see if and when an e-mail was opened by a data subject, and which links in the e-mail were called up by data subjects.

Such personal data collected in the tracking pixels contained in the newsletters are stored and analyzed by the controller in order to optimize the shipping of the newsletter, as well as to adapt the content of future newsletters even better to the interests of the data subject. These personal data will not be passed on to third parties. Data subjects are at any time entitled to revoke the respective separate declaration of consent issued by means of the double-opt-in procedure. After a revocation, these personal data will be deleted by the controller. The Schrödinger, Inc. automatically regards a withdrawal from the receipt of the newsletter as a revocation.

 **8\. Routine erasure and blocking of personal data**

The data controller shall process and store the personal data of the data subject only for the period necessary to achieve the purpose of storage, or as far as this is granted by the European legislator or other legislators in laws or regulations to which the controller is subject to. If the storage purpose is not applicable, or if a storage period prescribed by the European legislator or another competent legislator expires, the personal data are routinely blocked or erased in accordance with legal requirements.

 **9\. Rights of the data subject**

a) Right of confirmation

• Each data subject shall have the right granted by the European legislator to obtain from the controller the confirmation as to whether or not personal data concerning him or her are being processed. If a data subject wishes to avail himself of this right of confirmation, he or she may, at any time, contact any employee of the controller.

b) Right of access

• Each data subject shall have the right granted by the European legislator to obtain from the controller free information about his or her personal data stored at any time and a copy of this information. Furthermore, the European directives and regulations grant the data subject access to the following information:

o the purposes of the processing; o the categories of personal data concerned;   
o the recipients or categories of recipients to whom the personal data have been or will be disclosed, in particular recipients in third countries or international organisations;   
o where possible, the envisaged period for which the personal data will be stored, or, if not possible, the criteria used to determine that period;   
o the existence of the right to request from the controller rectification or erasure of personal data, or restriction of processing of personal data concerning the data subject, or to object to such processing;   
o the existence of the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority; o where the personal data are not collected from the data subject, any available information as to their source;   
o the existence of automated decision-making, including profiling, referred to in Article 22(1) and (4) of the GDPR and, at least in those cases, meaningful information about the logic involved, as well as the significance and envisaged consequences of such processing for the data subject.

• Furthermore, the data subject shall have a right to obtain information as to whether personal data are transferred to a third country or to an international organisation. Where this is the case, the data subject shall have the right to be informed of the appropriate safeguards relating to the transfer.

• If a data subject wishes to avail himself of this right of access, he or she may, at any time, contact any employee of the controller.

c) Right to rectification

• Each data subject shall have the right granted by the European legislator to obtain from the controller without undue delay the rectification of inaccurate personal data concerning him or her. Taking into account the purposes of the processing, the data subject shall have the right to have incomplete personal data completed, including by means of providing a supplementary statement.

• If a data subject wishes to exercise this right to rectification, he or she may, at any time, contact any employee of the controller.

d) Right to erasure (Right to be forgotten)

• Each data subject shall have the right granted by the European legislator to obtain from the controller the erasure of personal data concerning him or her without undue delay, and the controller shall have the obligation to erase personal data without undue delay where one of the following grounds applies, as long as the processing is not necessary:

o The personal data are no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which they were collected or otherwise processed.   
o The data subject withdraws consent to which the processing is based according to point (a) of Article 6(1) of the GDPR, or point (a) of Article 9(2) of the GDPR, and where there is no other legal ground for the processing.   
o The data subject objects to the processing pursuant to Article 21(1) of the GDPR and there are no overriding legitimate grounds for the processing, or the data subject objects to the processing pursuant to Article 21(2) of the GDPR.   
o The personal data have been unlawfully processed.  
o The personal data must be erased for compliance with a legal obligation in Union or Member State law to which the controller is subject.   
o The personal data have been collected in relation to the offer of information society services referred to in Article 8(1) of the GDPR.

• If one of the aforementioned reasons applies, and a data subject wishes to request the erasure of personal data stored by the Schrödinger, Inc., he or she may, at any time, contact any employee of the controller. An employee of Schrödinger, Inc. shall promptly ensure that the erasure request is complied with immediately.

• Where the controller has made personal data public and is obliged pursuant to Article 17(1) to erase the personal data, the controller, taking account of available technology and the cost of implementation, shall take reasonable steps, including technical measures, to inform other controllers processing the personal data that the data subject has requested erasure by such controllers of any links to, or copy or replication of, those personal data, as far as processing is not required. An employees of the Schrödinger, Inc. will arrange the necessary measures in individual cases.

 **e) Right of restriction of processing**

• Each data subject shall have the right granted by the European legislator to obtain from the controller restriction of processing where one of the following applies:

o The accuracy of the personal data is contested by the data subject, for a period enabling the controller to verify the accuracy of the personal data.   
o The processing is unlawful and the data subject opposes the erasure of the personal data and requests instead the restriction of their use instead.   
o The controller no longer needs the personal data for the purposes of the processing, but they are required by the data subject for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.   
o The data subject has objected to processing pursuant to Article 21(1) of the GDPR pending the verification whether the legitimate grounds of the controller override those of the data subject.

• If one of the aforementioned conditions is met, and a data subject wishes to request the restriction of the processing of personal data stored by the Schrödinger, Inc., he or she may at any time contact any employee of the controller. The employee of the Schrödinger, Inc. will arrange the restriction of the processing.

 **f) Right to data portability**

• Each data subject shall have the right granted by the European legislator, to receive the personal data concerning him or her, which was provided to a controller, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format. He or she shall have the right to transmit those data to another controller without hindrance from the controller to which the personal data have been provided, as long as the processing is based on consent pursuant to point (a) of Article 6(1) of the GDPR or point (a) of Article 9(2) of the GDPR, or on a contract pursuant to point (b) of Article 6(1) of the GDPR, and the processing is carried out by automated means, as long as the processing is not necessary for the performance of a task carried out in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority vested in the controller.

• Furthermore, in exercising his or her right to data portability pursuant to Article 20(1) of the GDPR, the data subject shall have the right to have personal data transmitted directly from one controller to another, where technically feasible and when doing so does not adversely affect the rights and freedoms of others.

• In order to assert the right to data portability, the data subject may at any time contact any employee of the Schrödinger, Inc.

 **g) Right to object**

• Each data subject shall have the right granted by the European legislator to object, on grounds relating to his or her particular situation, at any time, to processing of personal data concerning him or her, which is based on point (e) or (f) of Article 6(1) of the GDPR. This also applies to profiling based on these provisions.

• The Schrödinger, Inc. shall no longer process the personal data in the event of the objection, unless we can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for the processing which override the interests, rights and freedoms of the data subject, or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

• If the Schrödinger, Inc. processes personal data for direct marketing purposes, the data subject shall have the right to object at any time to processing of personal data concerning him or her for such marketing. This applies to profiling to the extent that it is related to such direct marketing. If the data subject objects to the Schrödinger, Inc. to the processing for direct marketing purposes, the Schrödinger, Inc. will no longer process the personal data for these purposes.

• In addition, the data subject has the right, on grounds relating to his or her particular situation, to object to processing of personal data concerning him or her by the Schrödinger, Inc. for scientific or historical research purposes, or for statistical purposes pursuant to Article 89(1) of the GDPR, unless the processing is necessary for the performance of a task carried out for reasons of public interest.

• In order to exercise the right to object, the data subject may contact any employee of the Schrödinger, Inc.. In addition, the data subject is free in the context of the use of information society services, and notwithstanding Directive 2002/58/EC, to use his or her right to object by automated means using technical specifications.

 **h) Automated individual decision-making, including profiling**

• Each data subject shall have the right granted by the European legislator not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing, including profiling, which produces legal effects concerning him or her, or similarly significantly affects him or her, as long as the decision (1) is not is necessary for entering into, or the performance of, a contract between the data subject and a data controller, or (2) is not authorised by Union or Member State law to which the controller is subject and which also lays down suitable measures to safeguard the data subject's rights and freedoms and legitimate interests, or (3) is not based on the data subject's explicit consent.

• If the decision (1) is necessary for entering into, or the performance of, a contract between the data subject and a data controller, or (2) it is based on the data subject's explicit consent, the Schrödinger, Inc. shall implement suitable measures to safeguard the data subject's rights and freedoms and legitimate interests, at least the right to obtain human intervention on the part of the controller, to express his or her point of view and contest the decision.

• If the data subject wishes to exercise the rights concerning automated individual decision-making, he or she may, at any time, contact any employee of the Schrödinger, Inc.

 **i) Right to withdraw data protection consent**

• Each data subject shall have the right granted by the European legislator to withdraw his or her consent to processing of his or her personal data at any time.

• If the data subject wishes to exercise the right to withdraw the consent, he or she may, at any time, contact any employee of the Schrödinger, Inc.

 **10\. Data protection for applications and the application procedures**

The data controller shall collect and process the personal data of applicants for the purpose of the processing of the application procedure. The processing may also be carried out electronically. This is the case, in particular, if an applicant submits corresponding application documents by e-mail or by means of a web form on the website to the controller. If the data controller concludes an employment contract with an applicant, the submitted data will be stored for the purpose of processing the employment relationship in compliance with legal requirements. If no employment contract is concluded with the applicant by the controller, the application documents shall be automatically erased two months after notification of the refusal decision, provided that no other legitimate interests of the controller are opposed to the erasure. Other legitimate interest in this relation is, e.g. a burden of proof in a procedure under the General Equal Treatment Act (AGG).

 **11\. Data protection provisions about the application and use of Google Analytics (with anonymization function)**

On this website, the controller has integrated the component of Google Analytics (with the anonymizer function). Google Analytics is a web analytics service. Web analytics is the collection, gathering, and analysis of data about the behavior of visitors to websites. A web analysis service collects, inter alia, data about the website from which a person has come (the so-called referrer), which sub-pages were visited, or how often and for what duration a sub-page was viewed. Web analytics are mainly used for the optimization of a website and in order to carry out a cost-benefit analysis of Internet advertising.

The operator of the Google Analytics component is Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Pkwy, Mountain View, CA 94043-1351, United States.

For the web analytics through Google Analytics the controller uses the application "_gat. _anonymizeIp". By means of this application the IP address of the Internet connection of the data subject is abridged by Google and anonymised when accessing our websites from a Member State of the European Union or another Contracting State to the Agreement on the European Economic Area.

The purpose of the Google Analytics component is to analyze the traffic on our website. Google uses the collected data and information, interalia, to evaluate the use of our website and to provide online reports, which show the activities on our websites, and to provide other services concerning the use of our Internet site for us.

Google Analytics places a cookie on the information technology system of the data subject. The definition of cookies is explained above. With the setting of the cookie, Google is enabled to analyze the use of our website. With each call-up to one of the individual pages of this Internet site, which is operated by the controller and into which a Google Analytics component was integrated, the Internet browser on the information technology system of the data subject will automatically submit data through the Google Analytics component for the purpose of online advertising and the settlement of commissions to Google. During the course of this technical procedure, the enterprise Google gains knowledge of personal information, such as the IP address of the data subject, which serves Google, inter alia, to understand the origin of visitors and clicks, and subsequently create commission settlements.

The cookie is used to store personal information, such as the access time, the location from which the access was made, and the frequency of visits of our website by the data subject. With each visit to our Internet site, such personal data, including the IP address of the Internet access used by the data subject, will be transmitted to Google in the United States of America. These personal data are stored by Google in the United States of America. Google may pass these personal data collected through the technical procedure to third parties.

The data subject may, as stated above, prevent the setting of cookies through our website at any time by means of a corresponding adjustment of the web browser used and thus permanently deny the setting of cookies. Such an adjustment to the Internet browser used would also prevent Google Analytics from setting a cookie on the information technology system of the data subject. In addition, cookies already in use by Google Analytics may be deleted at any time via a web browser or other software programs. In addition, the data subject has the possibility of objecting to a collection of data that are generated by Google Analytics, which is related to the use of this website, as well as the processing of this data by Google and the chance to preclude any such. For this purpose, the data subject must download a browser add-on under the link <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout> and install it. This browser add-on tells Google Analytics through a JavaScript, that any data and information about the visits of Internet pages may not be transmitted to Google Analytics. The installation of the browser add-ons is considered an objection by Google. If the information technology system of the data subject is later deleted, formatted, or newly installed, then the data subject must reinstall the browser add-ons to disable Google Analytics. If the browser add-on was uninstalled by the data subject or any other person who is attributable to their sphere of competence, or is disabled, it is possible to execute the reinstallation or reactivation of the browser add-ons.

Further information and the applicable data protection provisions of Google may be retrieved under <https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/> and under <http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html>. Google Analytics is further explained under the following Link <https://www.google.com/analytics/>.

 **12\. Data protection provisions about the application and use of Google+**

On this website, the controller has integrated the Google+ button as a component. Google+ is a so-called social network. A social network is a social meeting place on the Internet, an online community, which usually allows users to communicate with each other and interact in a virtual space. A social network may serve as a platform for the exchange of opinions and experiences, or enable the Internet community to provide personal or business-related information. Google+ allows users of the social network to include the creation of private profiles, upload photos and network through friend requests.

The operating company of Google+ is Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Pkwy, Mountain View, CA 94043-1351, UNITED STATES.

With each call-up to one of the individual pages of this website, which is operated by the controller and on which a Google+ button has been integrated, the Internet browser on the information technology system of the data subject automatically downloads a display of the corresponding Google+ button of Google through the respective Google+ button component. During the course of this technical procedure, Google is made aware of what specific sub-page of our website was visited by the data subject. More detailed information about Google+ is available under <https://developers.google.com/+/>.

If the data subject is logged in at the same time to Google+, Google recognizes with each call-up to our website by the data subject and for the entire duration of his or her stay on our Internet site, which specific sub-pages of our Internet page were visited by the data subject. This information is collected through the Google+ button and Google matches this with the respective Google+ account associated with the data subject.

If the data subject clicks on the Google+ button integrated on our website and thus gives a Google+ 1 recommendation, then Google assigns this information to the personal Google+ user account of the data subject and stores the personal data. Google stores the Google+ 1 recommendation of the data subject, making it publicly available in accordance with the terms and conditions accepted by the data subject in this regard. Subsequently, a Google+ 1 recommendation given by the data subject on this website together with other personal data, such as the Google+ account name used by the data subject and the stored photo, is stored and processed on other Google services, such as search-engine results of the Google search engine, the Google account of the data subject or in other places, e.g. on Internet pages, or in relation to advertisements. Google is also able to link the visit to this website with other personal data stored on Google. Google further records this personal information with the purpose of improving or optimizing the various Google services.

Through the Google+ button, Google receives information that the data subject visited our website, if the data subject at the time of the call-up to our website is logged in to Google+. This occurs regardless of whether the data subject clicks or doesn’t click on the Google+ button.

If the data subject does not wish to transmit personal data to Google, he or she may prevent such transmission by logging out of his Google+ account before calling up our website. Further information and the data protection provisions of Google may be retrieved under <https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>. More references from Google about the Google+ 1 button may be obtained under <https://developers.google.com/+/web/buttons-policy>.

 **13\. Data protection provisions about the application and use of LinkedIn**

The controller has integrated components of the LinkedIn Corporation on this website. LinkedIn is a web-based social network that enables users with existing business contacts to connect and to make new business contacts. Over 400 million registered people in more than 200 countries use LinkedIn. Thus, LinkedIn is currently the largest platform for business contacts and one of the most visited websites in the world.

The operating company of LinkedIn is LinkedIn Corporation, 2029 Stierlin Court Mountain View, CA 94043, UNITED STATES. For privacy matters outside of the UNITED STATES LinkedIn Ireland, Privacy Policy Issues, Wilton Plaza, Wilton Place, Dublin 2, Ireland, is responsible.

With each call-up to one of the individual pages of this Internet site, which is operated by the controller and on which a LinkedIn component (LinkedIn plug-in) was integrated, the Internet browser on the information technology system of the data subject is automatically prompted to the download of a display of the corresponding LinkedIn component of LinkedIn. Further information about the LinkedIn plug-in may be accessed under <https://developer.linkedin.com/plugins>. During the course of this technical procedure, LinkedIn gains knowledge of what specific sub-page of our website was visited by the data subject.

If the data subject is logged in at the same time on LinkedIn, LinkedIn detects with every call-up to our website by the data subject—and for the entire duration of their stay on our Internet site—which specific sub-page of our Internet page was visited by the data subject. This information is collected through the LinkedIn component and associated with the respective LinkedIn account of the data subject. If the data subject clicks on one of the LinkedIn buttons integrated on our website, then LinkedIn assigns this information to the personal LinkedIn user account of the data subject and stores the personal data.

LinkedIn receives information via the LinkedIn component that the data subject has visited our website, provided that the data subject is logged in at LinkedIn at the time of the call-up to our website. This occurs regardless of whether the person clicks on the LinkedIn button or not. If such a transmission of information to LinkedIn is not desirable for the data subject, then he or she may prevent this by logging off from their LinkedIn account before a call-up to our website is made.

LinkedIn provides under <https://www.linkedin.com/psettings/guest-controls> the possibility to unsubscribe from e-mail messages, SMS messages and targeted ads, as well as the ability to manage ad settings. LinkedIn also uses affiliates such as Eire, Google Analytics, BlueKai, DoubleClick, Nielsen, Comscore, Eloqua, and Lotame. The setting of such cookies may be denied under <https://www.linkedin.com/legal/cookie-policy>. The applicable privacy policy for LinkedIn is available under <https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy>. The LinkedIn Cookie Policy is available under <https://www.linkedin.com/legal/cookie-policy>.

 **14\. Data protection provisions about the application and use of Twitter**

On this website, the controller has integrated components of Twitter. Twitter is a multilingual, publicly-accessible microblogging service on which users may publish and spread so-called ‘tweets,’ e.g. short messages, which are limited to 280 characters. These short messages are available for everyone, including those who are not logged on to Twitter. The tweets are also displayed to so-called followers of the respective user. Followers are other Twitter users who follow a user's tweets. Furthermore, Twitter allows you to address a wide audience via hashtags, links or retweets.

The operating company of Twitter is Twitter, Inc., 1355 Market Street, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, UNITED STATES.

With each call-up to one of the individual pages of this Internet site, which is operated by the controller and on which a Twitter component (Twitter button) was integrated, the Internet browser on the information technology system of the data subject is automatically prompted to download a display of the corresponding Twitter component of Twitter. Further information about the Twitter buttons is available under <https://about.twitter.com/de/resources/buttons>. During the course of this technical procedure, Twitter gains knowledge of what specific sub-page of our website was visited by the data subject. The purpose of the integration of the Twitter component is a retransmission of the contents of this website to allow our users to introduce this web page to the digital world and increase our visitor numbers.

If the data subject is logged in at the same time on Twitter, Twitter detects with every call-up to our website by the data subject and for the entire duration of their stay on our Internet site which specific sub-page of our Internet page was visited by the data subject. This information is collected through the Twitter component and associated with the respective Twitter account of the data subject. If the data subject clicks on one of the Twitter buttons integrated on our website, then Twitter assigns this information to the personal Twitter user account of the data subject and stores the personal data.

Twitter receives information via the Twitter component that the data subject has visited our website, provided that the data subject is logged in on Twitter at the time of the call-up to our website. This occurs regardless of whether the person clicks on the Twitter component or not. If such a transmission of information to Twitter is not desirable for the data subject, then he or she may prevent this by logging off from their Twitter account before a call-up to our website is made.

The applicable data protection provisions of Twitter may be accessed under <https://twitter.com/privacy?lang=en>.

 **15\. Data protection provisions about the application and use of YouTube**

On this website, the controller has integrated components of YouTube. YouTube is an Internet video portal that enables video publishers to set video clips and other users free of charge, which also provides free viewing, review and commenting on them. YouTube allows you to publish all kinds of videos, so you can access both full movies and TV broadcasts, as well as music videos, trailers, and videos made by users via the Internet portal.

The operating company of YouTube is YouTube, LLC, 901 Cherry Ave., San Bruno, CA 94066, UNITED STATES. The YouTube, LLC is a subsidiary of Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Pkwy, Mountain View, CA 94043-1351, UNITED STATES.

With each call-up to one of the individual pages of this Internet site, which is operated by the controller and on which a YouTube component (YouTube video) was integrated, the Internet browser on the information technology system of the data subject is automatically prompted to download a display of the corresponding YouTube component. Further information about YouTube may be obtained under <https://www.youtube.com/yt/about/en/>. During the course of this technical procedure, YouTube and Google gain knowledge of what specific sub-page of our website was visited by the data subject.

If the data subject is logged in on YouTube, YouTube recognizes with each call-up to a sub-page that contains a YouTube video, which specific sub-page of our Internet site was visited by the data subject. This information is collected by YouTube and Google and assigned to the respective YouTube account of the data subject. YouTube and Google will receive information through the YouTube component that the data subject has visited our website, if the data subject at the time of the call to our website is logged in on YouTube; this occurs regardless of whether the person clicks on a YouTube video or not. If such a transmission of this information to YouTube and Google is not desirable for the data subject, the delivery may be prevented if the data subject logs off from their own YouTube account before a call-up to our website is made.

YouTube's data protection provisions, available at <https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>, provide information about the collection, processing and use of personal data by YouTube and Google.

 **16\. Legal basis for the processing**

Art. 6(1) lit. a GDPR serves as the legal basis for processing operations for which we obtain consent for a specific processing purpose. If the processing of personal data is necessary for the performance of a contract to which the data subject is party, as is the case, for example, when processing operations are necessary for the supply of goods or to provide any other service, the processing is based on Article 6(1) lit. b GDPR. The same applies to such processing operations which are necessary for carrying out pre-contractual measures, for example in the case of inquiries concerning our products or services. Is our company subject to a legal obligation by which processing of personal data is required, such as for the fulfillment of tax obligations, the processing is based on Art. 6(1) lit. c GDPR. In rare cases, the processing of personal data may be necessary to protect the vital interests of the data subject or of another natural person. This would be the case, for example, if a visitor were injured in our company and his name, age, health insurance data or other vital information would have to be passed on to a doctor, hospital or other third party. Then the processing would be based on Art. 6(1) lit. d GDPR. Finally, processing operations could be based on Article 6(1) lit. f GDPR. This legal basis is used for processing operations which are not covered by any of the abovementioned legal grounds, if processing is necessary for the purposes of the legitimate interests pursued by our company or by a third party, except where such interests are overridden by the interests or fundamental rights and freedoms of the data subject which require protection of personal data. Such processing operations are particularly permissible because they have been specifically mentioned by the European legislator. He considered that a legitimate interest could be assumed if the data subject is a client of the controller (Recital 47 Sentence 2 GDPR). 18. The legitimate interests pursued by the controller or by a third party Where the processing of personal data is based on Article 6(1) lit. f GDPR our legitimate interest is to carry out our business in favor of the well-being of all our employees and the shareholders. 19. Period for which the personal data will be stored The criteria used to determine the period of storage of personal data is the respective statutory retention period. After expiration of that period, the corresponding data is routinely deleted, as long as it is no longer necessary for the fulfillment of the contract or the initiation of a contract.

 **17\. Provision of personal data as statutory or contractual requirement; Requirement necessary to enter into a contract; Obligation of the data subject to provide the personal data; possible consequences of failure to provide such data**

We clarify that the provision of personal data is partly required by law (e.g. tax regulations) or can also result from contractual provisions (e.g. information on the contractual partner). Sometimes it may be necessary to conclude a contract that the data subject provides us with personal data, which must subsequently be processed by us. The data subject is, for example, obliged to provide us with personal data when our company signs a contract with him or her. The non-provision of the personal data would have the consequence that the contract with the data subject could not be concluded. Before personal data is provided by the data subject, the data subject must contact any employee. The employee clarifies to the data subject whether the provision of the personal data is required by law or contract or is necessary for the conclusion of the contract, whether there is an obligation to provide the personal data and the consequences of non-provision of the personal data.

 **18\. Existence of automated decision-making**

As a responsible company, we do not use automatic decision-making or profiling.

 **19\. Payment Method: Data protection provisions about the use of PayPal as a payment processor**

On this website, the controller has integrated components of PayPal. PayPal is an online payment service provider. Payments are processed via so-called PayPal accounts, which represent virtual private or business accounts. PayPal is also able to process virtual payments through credit cards when a user does not have a PayPal account. A PayPal account is managed via an e-mail address, which is why there are no classic account numbers. PayPal makes it possible to trigger online payments to third parties or to receive payments. PayPal also accepts trustee functions and offers buyer protection services.

The European operating company of PayPal is PayPal (Europe) S.à.r.l. & Cie. S.C.A., 22-24 Boulevard Royal, 2449 Luxembourg, Luxembourg.

If the data subject chooses "PayPal" as the payment option in the online shop during the ordering process, we automatically transmit the data of the data subject to PayPal. By selecting this payment option, the data subject agrees to the transfer of personal data required for payment processing.

The personal data transmitted to PayPal is usually first name, last name, address, email address, IP address, telephone number, mobile phone number, or other data necessary for payment processing.The processing of the purchase contract also requires such personal data, which are in connection with the respective order.

The transmission of the data is aimed at payment processing and fraud prevention. The controller will transfer personal data to PayPal, in particular, if a legitimate interest in the transmission is given. The personal data exchanged between PayPal and the controller for the processing of the data will be transmitted by PayPal to economic credit agencies. This transmission is intended for identity and creditworthiness checks.

PayPal will, if necessary, pass on personal data to affiliates and service providers or subcontractors to the extent that this is necessary to fulfill contractual obligations or for data to be processed in the order.

The data subject has the possibility to revoke consent for the handling of personal data at any time from PayPal. A revocation shall not have any effect on personal data which must be processed, used or transmitted in accordance with (contractual) payment processing.

The applicable data protection provisions of PayPal may be retrieved under <https://www.paypal.com/us/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full>.
